Zach Moazeni

zach.moazeni@gmail.com / 231.676.4510

Summary

I am a senior full stack developer who can work on all pieces of an application from browser to server and from concept to optimization. I am not a designer, but I have an eye for user experience and I can help mold user friendly software. I am a strong believer in using the right tool for the job and not forcing technology just because it is fun or shiny. Finally, I have a lot of experience working independently as well as with teams in remote environments.

Work History

Aug 2012 - Present: Senior Developer at Harvest

I deal with a wide range of software and operational issues at Harvest. I joined as a senior software developer and tackled many projects that impacted the core of the product and the business.

Most notably, I lead the redevelopment of our Projects area which is a core concept to our application and our most heavily used area for management users. We rolled this out slowly, experimenting with different interfaces and dealt with customer issues as they came up, often causing us to re-evaluate our rollout. Common responsibilities include: Planning the feature set and plan for development. Managing projects and other developers to make sure we meet our goals. Developing the backend server architecture in Ruby/Rails and the frontend in Javascript and Coffeescript. Triaging bugs and releasing fixes for them.

In early 2015, I transitioned into a specialized role to manage our application's database interactions with Percona MySQL. This put me in a gray area between typical feature development and DevOps. My responsibilities have largely consisted of identifying weak software designs between our application and databases. Finding and optimizing slow queries. Evaluating metrics to make determination on caching worthiness. Managing MySQL upgrades and experimental tuning without downtime. Dealing with large migrations our team needs to accomplish for refactoring or new feature development. Diagnosing and fixing existing database/application issues as well as looking forward to prevent future issues early.

One of my most notable projects since assuming this role has been the entire refactoring and optimization of our application reporting software design without downtime or customer issues. This involved weeks of planning and live migrating one of our largest tables with half a billion rows.

I still participate in feature development, but the health of the application-database interaction is my primary responsibility. Other responsibilities have included interviewing candidates and mentoring junior developers.

Key technologies: Ruby, Rails, MySQL, Statsd/Graphite/Grafana, Percona Toolkit, Redis, Memcache, Sidekiq, Ansible, Kibana, Elasticsearch, Heroku (for smaller applications), Javascript/Coffeescript, Backbone.js.

Feb 2011 - Aug 2012: Developer at Collectiveldea

I was a senior software developer contracting on a variety of projects and clients. The most notable was for Apple Inc. as a backend server developer for their *RetailMe* application which all in-store employees used for day-to-day responsibilities. This dealt with negotiating and designing multiple independent microservices that were used as a cohesive whole. I also spent a great deal of time understanding their localization and translation workflow and implementing key features in certain services to accommodate and aid the management of that process.

Key technologies: Ruby, Rails, MongoDB, PostgreSQL, Heroku.

May 2010 - Feb 2011: Independent Contractor

I worked as an independent contractor working on a variety of small and medium sized projects while managing clients relationships. Notable projects included writing an iPad dashboard from scratch and a working as a developer on a team for an affiliate tracking application with heavy data processing.

Key technologies: Ruby, Rails, PostgreSQL, iOS

Jan 2007 - May 2010: Developer at Elevator Up

I wore many hats at Elevator Up as the first employee. I was primarily a software developer working on different client work for startup and established companies alike. I also was responsible for Elevator Up's application hosting services. Finally, we launched several startup products and I was the key developer for each of them.

Key technologies: Ruby, Rails, ExpressionEngine, Drupal, PHP, Java.

2004 - May 2007: Early Career

I worked primarily in Java J2EE across several companies prior to graduating college.

Open Source

I have developed and maintained a few open source libraries in my free time.

http://zmoazeni.github.io/harvested/ - most notably is the ruby wrapper around the Harvest API. I started this before I joined Harvest and have continued to maintain it now while I try to find a maintainer to adopt it.

<u>http://zmoazeni.github.io/csscss/</u> - a command line tool that parses and analyzes CSS and reports duplication that can help developers reduce unnecessary explicit rules.

I am fairly active on GitHub dealing with our various dependencies. You can browse my activity feed https://github.com/zmoazeni to see relevant issues and pull requests I've created over the years.

Technology

Even while the majority of my professional experience has dealt with Ruby, I continue to keep myself informed on other languages and technologies. I often create hobby projects to reinforce what I learn. Here is a list of relevant technology that I have worked with, either in a professional capacity on projects or as a hobbyist.

Specialist

Ruby, Rails, MySQL, PostgreSQL, Redis, MongoDB, Ubuntu, Javascript, jQuery, Prototype.js, ES6, Backbone.js, Knockout.js, Coffeescript, Bootstrap, Foundation Sites, HTML5, CSS, Sass, Less, Heroku, Git and GitHub, SVN, test-unit, rspec.

Competent

Node.js, Haskell, Rust, Go, Java, Scala, Clojure, Python 2 and 3, Django, PHP, Electron, Ember.js, React, Ansible, Chef, Puppet, AWS, Nginx, Mecurial, Elasticsearch, ExpressionEngine.

Hobbyist

C, C++, D, R, Qt, Elixir, Perl, iOS, Android, Angular v1 and v2/4, Google Cloud Hosting.

Education

Graduated with Bachelors of Science in Computer Science from Grand Valley State University in 2006.